<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: dnf | Thejdeep]]></title>
  <link href="http://thejdeep.github.io/blog/categories/dnf/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thejdeep.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-04T15:45:44+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://thejdeep.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thejdeep Gudivada]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[YUM vs DNF Plugin API]]></title>
    <link href="http://thejdeep.github.io/blog/2015/07/02/yum-vs-dnf-plugin-api/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-02T07:10:20+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thejdeep.github.io/blog/2015/07/02/yum-vs-dnf-plugin-api</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last week or so, I was looking to port a YUM Plugin to DNF after considering the various potential advantages of DNF. During the process of conversion, I noticed a few differences in the Plugin API of both:</p>

<ul>
<li>DNF plugin API doesn&rsquo;t allow you to read arguments supplied through the CLI, atleast for now. Unlike the YUM Plugin API, where the <em>conduit</em> available in the <em>args_hook</em> has a function <em>getArgs()</em> which allows me to access the CLI arguments</li>
<li>There are a fewer number of hooks which the DNF Plugin API supports</li>
<li>The DNF plugin <strong>has</strong> to inherit from a parent class <em>dnf.cli</em></li>
</ul>


<p>To make the stand on this issue more clearer, I have written a basic <em>Hello World</em> plugin using both API&rsquo;s.</p>

<p>A <em>Hello World</em> plugin written using the YUM Plugin API
<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/7146d5311940ae03d068.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>from yum.plugins import PluginYumExit , TYPE_CORE, TYPE_INTERACTIVE

requires_api_version = &#39;2.3&#39;
plugin_type = (TYPE_CORE, TYPE_INTERACTIVE)

def init_hook(conduit):
        print &quot;Hello World&quot;
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Similarly, a <em>Hello World</em> plugin written using the DNF Plugin API
<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/d2d78776110e37699e9b.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>from __future__ import absolute_import
from __future__ import unicode_literals
from dnfpluginscore import _

import dnf
import dnf.exceptions
import os

class Test(dnf.Plugin):
        name=&#39;test&#39;
        def __init__(self,base,cli):
                super(Test,self).__init__(base,cli)
                self.base=base
                self.cli=cli
        def config(self):
                print &quot;Hello World&quot;
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[YUM vs DNF]]></title>
    <link href="http://thejdeep.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/yum-vs-dnf/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-01T22:04:07+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thejdeep.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/yum-vs-dnf</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot has been said already about which of the two RPM-based package managers to choose from - YUM or DNF. All the ramblings must have clearly started when Jan from the DNF team proclaimed that <em>YUM is dead, long live DNF!</em> in one of his famous rants on why Fedora 22 has its default package manager as DNF and not the faithful old YUM. You can find that great read <a href="http://dnf.baseurl.org/2015/05/11/yum-is-dead-long-live-dnf/" target="_blank">here</a>. He also states the following reasons why YUM failed :</p>

<ul>
<li>Broken dependency solving algorithm</li>
<li>Undocumented API</li>
<li>Inability to refactor internal functions</li>
</ul>


<p>But, people seem to like YUM way better than DNF because it sounds better. Atleast, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/36a1wq/yum_is_dead_long_live_dnf/" target="_blank">this</a> thread on Reddit says so.</p>

<p>On the similar point of view, there are a plenty of advantages in using DNF. Few of them are :</p>

<ul>
<li>Uses a successful low-level SAT solver library for resolving dependencies. SUSE has been using this in production over the years</li>
<li>Downloading of the repository metadata and packages is done by Librepo, which is another component used by DNF.</li>
<li>Proven to be times faster than YUM. You can try running a list command in each.</li>
</ul>


<p>Although, DNF seems to fit the puzzle, there are a few disadvantages that might hold it back :</p>

<ul>
<li>Its a Work In Progress. The DNF team is working hard in porting all the legacy stuff of YUM to DNF. This might take some time.</li>
<li>Hogs bandwidth. Silently downloading metadata information in the background. Although, this can be tweaked and disabled in the configuration file, it poses to be a problem. You can read more about this issue <a href="https://hedayatvk.wordpress.com/2014/07/26/the-shiny-new-dnf-and-why-i-prefer-yum/" target="_blank">here</a> where the author states why this makes him prefer YUM over DNF.</li>
<li>DNF Plugin API isn&rsquo;t a fully baked product. Currently, the DNF API doesn&rsquo;t support reading command line arguments supplied through the CLI.</li>
</ul>


<p>In conclusion, if performance is a concern, DNF is the way to go.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
